const ssc2000Questions = [
    {
      question: "In which year did India conduct its second successful nuclear test, codenamed 'Operation Shakti'?",
      options: ["1998", "2000", "2003", "2005"],
      correctAnswer: "1998",
    },
    {
      question: "Which Indian cricketer scored 186 runs against New Zealand in the ICC KnockOut Trophy in 2000?",
      options: ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Rahul Dravid", "Sourav Ganguly", "Virender Sehwag"],
      correctAnswer: "Sourav Ganguly",
    },
    {
      question: "Which country hosted the Summer Olympics in the year 2000?",
      options: ["United States", "China", "Australia", "Japan"],
      correctAnswer: "Australia",
    },
    {
      question: "Who won the Nobel Prize in Physics in the year 2000 for their work on the quantum Hall effect?",
      options: ["Albert Einstein", "Enrico Fermi", "Robert Laughlin, Horst Störmer, and Daniel Tsui", "Richard Feynman"],
      correctAnswer: "Robert Laughlin, Horst Störmer, and Daniel Tsui",
    },
    {
      question: "Which Indian film won the Academy Award (Oscar) for Best Foreign Language Film in 2000?",
      options: ["Lagaan", "Dilwale Dulhania Le Jayenge", "Kabhi Khushi Kabhie Gham", "Mother India"],
      correctAnswer: "Lagaan",
    },
    {
      question: "Who became the President of the United States in the year 2000?",
      options: ["Bill Clinton", "George W. Bush", "Barack Obama", "Ronald Reagan"],
      correctAnswer: "George W. Bush",
    },
    {
      question: "The year 2000 was celebrated as the 'Year of Dialogue Among Civilizations' by which international organization?",
      options: ["United Nations", "World Health Organization (WHO)", "International Monetary Fund (IMF)", "World Trade Organization (WTO)"],
      correctAnswer: "United Nations",
    },
    {
      question: "Which iconic search engine was founded by Larry Page and Sergey Brin in 1998 and gained significant popularity in the early 2000s?",
      options: ["Yahoo", "Bing", "Google", "Ask Jeeves"],
      correctAnswer: "Google",
    },
    {
      question: "The Kargil War between India and Pakistan took place in the year:",
      options: ["1999", "2000", "2001", "2002"],
      correctAnswer: "1999",
    },
    {
      question: "Which Indian won the Miss World title in the year 2000?",
      options: ["Aishwarya Rai", "Priyanka Chopra", "Sushmita Sen", "Lara Dutta"],
      correctAnswer: "Aishwarya Rai",
    },
  ];
  
  export default ssc2000Questions;
  